VICTOR MERSEGUEL

Front-End Developer

Carcavelos, Cascais

+351 935 715 802 | merseguel@gmail.com

Portfólio: <u>www.victormerseguel.com/dev</u> | GitHub: <u>/victormerseguel</u>

PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE

Front-End Developer with over 3 years of experience in technologies such as ReactJS, Next.js,

JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, focused on creating optimized and scalable user interfaces. What I

enjoy most about programming is translating design and user experience requirements into code

using best practices, bridging two constantly evolving worlds.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks: React, Next.js, SASS

Tools: Git, GitHub, Figma, Photoshop

Agile Methodologies: Scrum, Kanban, Continuous Integration Testing

Additional Skills: SEO, Web Performance, UX/UI Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer at Guia L'Onde Portal

Carcavelos | January 2024 - February 2024

Front-End development and UI design for the new Guia L'Onde portal using React.js,

Email.js, localStorage, and hreflang attribute management for multilingual routes.

Deploy: https://www.guialonde.com/

Front-End Developer for Luciana Castellano Project

Carcavelos | September 2023 - February 2024

Front-End development and UI design for Luciana Castellano's website using Next.js

with a focus on performance and SEO results. The application hosts multiple landing

page routes with seasonal openings.

Deploy: https://luciana-castellano.vercel.app/

Freelancer – Web Developer and Web Designer

Carcavelos | February 2022 – Present

Development of professional websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and

Next.js, applying modern practices and scalable architecture through

componentization.

UI design, creating visually appealing and intuitive pages.

Translating business requirements into technical solutions through close collaboration

with clients.

Utilizing Git and GitHub for version control and team collaboration.

EDUCATION

Web Development

React Complete – Origamid (December 2023)

Creative Coding: Making Visuals with JavaScript – Domestika (October 2023)

Front-End Development Course – Matheus Battisti (October 2023)

JavaScript Fundamentals – Erick Wendel (August 2023)

BA in Performing Arts

Fundação das Artes de São Caetano do Sul (February 2006 – September 2009)

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native

English: Intermediate / Advanced